<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<!--If you edit this file, please place it in a safe place since future exports will overwrite this automatically generated reference file.-->
<c74object name="pdm.queue.manager">
<metadatalist>
<metadata name="author">Philip Meyer</metadata>
<metadata name="tag">buffers</metadata>
<metadata name="tag">queues</metadata>
</metadatalist>
<attributelist>
  <attribute name="buffers" get="1" set="1" size="2" type="symbol">
    <digest>Names of the queue and metadata buffers</digest>
    <description>
      Specifies the names of the two buffers used by the queue manager:
      - First argument: Name of the queue buffer that holds the data
      - Second argument: Name of the metadata buffer that holds read/write positions, loop lengths, and every values
    </description>
  </attribute>
</attributelist>
<methodlist>
  <method name="write">
    <arglist>
      <arg name="channel" optional="1" type="int" />
      <arg name="value" optional="0" type="float" />
    </arglist>
    <digest>Write a value to the specified channel(s)</digest>
    <description>
      Writes a value to the specified channel in the queue buffer.
      If channel is 0, the value is written to all channels.
    </description>
  </method>
  <method name="back">
    <arglist>
      <arg name="channel" optional="1" type="int" />
      <arg name="steps" optional="1" type="int" />
    </arglist>
    <digest>Move the write position backward</digest>
    <description>
      Moves the write position backward by the specified number of steps.
      If channel is 0, the position is moved for all channels.
      If steps is omitted, it defaults to 1.
    </description>
  </method>
  <method name="looplen">
    <arglist>
      <arg name="channel" optional="1" type="int" />
      <arg name="length" optional="0" type="int" />
    </arglist>
    <digest>Set the loop length for the specified channel(s)</digest>
    <description>
      Sets the loop length for the specified channel.
      If channel is 0, the length is set for all channels.
      The length must be a positive number.
    </description>
  </method>
  <method name="every">
    <arglist>
      <arg name="channel" optional="1" type="int" />
      <arg name="every" optional="0" type="int" />
    </arglist>
    <digest>Set the every value for the specified channel(s)</digest>
    <description>
      Sets the every value for the specified channel.
      If channel is 0, the value is set for all channels.
      The every value must be a positive number.
    </description>
  </method>
  <method name="dump">
    <digest>Dump the current state of the queue buffer</digest>
    <description>
      Outputs a dictionary containing the state of all the queues,
      including buffer names, sizes, channel counts, and queue states.
    </description>
  </method>
</methodlist>
<description>
    Write to queues in a multichannel buffer, and set parameters for the queue reader. 
    
</description>
<digest>Manage multi-channel queue buffers</digest>
<seealsolist>
  <seealso name="pdm.queue.reader" />
  <seealso name="pdm.queue.peek" />
</seealsolist>
</c74object>
